# GURUPRASATH

+91-7904236163 **Email** gprasath20@gmail.com **GitHub** 



**Phone** 

https://www.github.com/guru6163

#### **PROFILE INFO**

SOFTWARE

Skilled Software Engineer with expertise in building complex web applications using React.js and related technologies. I possess a strong understanding of front-end web development technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript frameworks. Additionally, I have experience in version control systems such as Git, and testing and debugging code.

#### MY SKILLS

- Python
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.js
- Redux
- Node.js / Express
- Docker
- TailwindCSS
- AntDesign
- Html / CSS
- Webpack
- · CI/CD

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Engineering -Computer Science** 

Sathyabama Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, India 2018 - 2022

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Software Engineer Aidaptive**

ENGINEER

Sept 2022 - Current

- · Created and Published NPM Package.
- Collaborated in Angular TypeScript to develop certain Features
- Modified SDKs to adapt to new conditions
- Created Code-Samples and JSON Templates for Client Integration.

# **Frontend Developer Shloka Concepts**

March 2022 - Sept 2022

- Collaborated in JavaScript, React JS, and Redux to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance
- Developed a Membership, event, and legal platform technology solution and automated internal process
- Developed and Implemented web applications with third-party CSS Frameworks like Ant-Design and Prime React.
- Developed an E-commerce Application for B2B Sellers.
- Mentored an Intern and helped him achieve professional growth and personal goals

# **Software Intern BloomLync Technologies**

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022

- · Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs and improving functionality.
- Produced clean, validation-ready code for project needs.

## SIDE-PROJECTS

# Valarona

https://cozy-paprenjak-d7aa2a.netlify.app/

# **Ecommerce Site**

- Complete Frontend made with React and TypeScript.
- Redux Toolkit for Global State Management.
- PrimeReact for Components, Used Formik and React Hooks Form for Form Validation, CRUD Functionality Implemented, Backend -JSON Placeholder APIs

# Dracosium **Blog Site**

https://github.com/guru6163/dracosium

- Complete Frontend Made with Next.js and TypeScript.
- · Used TailwindCss for Styling, Implemented Server Side Rendering, Backend as Sanity.io, Responsive UI